William Temple Franklin-Charles Pemberton Fox Legal Records 1692-1881 Mss.B.F86L
American Philosophical Society
William Temple Franklin-Charles Pemberton Fox Legal Records
1692-1881
Mss.B.F86L
American Philosophical Society
2.0 Linear feet
Associates of Benjamin Franklin and his grandson William Temple Franklin, the Fox family of Philadelphia were holders of considerable property in Philadelphia during the eighteenth century and speculated extensively in lands in the northern and western parts of the state. The son of Dr. George Fox, Charles Pemberton Fox inherited the estate Champlost at which the papers of Benjamin Franklin were left in 1790. He donated the collection to the American Philosophical Society in 1840. The legal records that comprise the William Temple Frankln-Charles Pemberton Fox collection relate to real property held by members of the Fox family and to the land holdings and financial interests of George Fox's close friend, William Temple Franklin. The collection includes about 100 deeds for properties in or near Philadelphia and in Luzerne County, Pa., along with a small quantity (about 31 items) of miscellaneous correspondence addressed to George Fox by Gouverneur Morris, Robert Morris, N. Cantwell Jones, Thomas Eddy, and others; and from William Constable and Sir Robert Herries and Co. (17 pieces) relating to the investments of William Temple Franklin.
2 linear feet
Fox family
Franklin, William Temple, 1760-1823
Biographical/Historical note
Associates and friends of Benjamin Franklin and his family, the Fox family came to Philadelphia in 1686, when the Quaker convert Justinian Fox (1673-1718) arrived aboard the Desire from his native Plymouth, England. Justinian's son Joseph Fox (ca.1710-1779) prospered after taking an apprenticeship with the carpenter James Portues, a founder of the Carpenters' Company, acquiring substantial property holdings in the city and serving in offices ranging from City Commissioner to Member of the Pennsylvania Assembly, including two stints as Speaker and one as a member of the Committee of Correspondence, a group responsible for communications with the colony's Agents in London, Benjamin Franklin and Richard Jackson. Read out of the Philadelphia Yearly Meeting in 1756 for refusal to withdraw from public office, and for "having violated our testimony against war," Fox's principaled refusal to accept Continental money for debts owed him in 1775 fueled rumors that he held Loyalist sympathies during the Revolution. He was a member of the revived American Philosophical Society at the time its merger with the American Society in 1769.
Joseph and his wife Elizabeth Mickle (1729-1805) had thirteen children, of whom only six survived to adulthood. These six, however, continued the family's prosperity. Their daughter Thomazine Fox (1748-1821) married into the Roberts family, while sons George (1759-1828) and Samuel Mickel Fox I (1763-1808) distinguished themselves in business and intellect. George, who was elected a member of the American Philosophical Society in 1784, represented Philadelphia in the Assembly in 1800, and was widely known as an organizer and director of the Delaware and Chesapeake Canal and as one of the early supporters of the bank of North America, of which he was Director from 1818 until 1828. He traveled extensively in France in the 1770s and 1780s, nearly dying at the chateau of the Comte de Champlost in 1780. He named his estate Champlost, built on the property that his grandfather Justinian Fox had inherited from James Portues.
Samuel Mickle Fox I served in a number of public offices, including the City Council, the Common Council (1793-1797), and the Upper Chamber (1797-1800), and he was both an incorporator of the Bank of Pennsylvania and its President from 1797-1808. After the Indian treaties of 1784 and 1785, Samuel and his brother George acquired immense tracts of land in northwestern Pennsylvania near the Allegheny River north of the Clarion that were patented in 1796. At his death, Samuel held 118,000 acres.
Samuel's son George (1806-1882) was born in a house on the southeast corner of 5th and Chestnut Streets in Philadelphia. He studied medicine at the University of Pennsylvania, graduating with an AB in 1825 and MD in 1828. A prominent surgeon and Fellow of the College of Physicians, Fox was a member of the delegation from the College of Physicians to the organizing convention of the American Medical Association in 1847.
Scope and Contents note
The legal records that comprise the William Temple Franklin-Charles Pemberton Fox collection relate to real property held by members of the Fox family and to the land holdings and financial interests of George Fox's close friend, William Temple Franklin. The collection includes about 100 deeds for properties in or near Philadelphia and in Luzerne County, Pa., along with a small quantity (about 31 items) of miscellaneous correspondence addressed to George Fox by Gouverneur Morris, Robert Morris, N. Cantwell Jones, Thomas Eddy, and others; and from William Constable and Sir Robert Herries and Co. (17 pieces) relating to the investments of William Temple Franklin.
Individuals named in these deeds include Joseph Fox, George Fox, Samuel Mickle Fox, Charles Pemberton Fox, and other members of their families on the one hand, and on the other, Mary Ball, Edward Shippen Burd, George Clymer, Gavin Hamilton, Henry Hill, John Lukens, Samuel Mickle, Israel Pemberton, Samuel Pleasants, Samuel Rhoads, Jr., Robert Strettell, William Wallace, Nicholas Waln. The documents consist primarily of deeds, but include a few mortgages, leases, and other instruments.
Related Archival Materials note
Several other collections at the APS relate to William Temple Franklin, including:
William Temple Franklin Papers
William Temple Franklin-George Fox Collection
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Charles Pemberton Fox, 1840.
Early American History Note
This portion of the Fox Family Collection at the APS contains information on their land holdings in western and northern Pennsylvania during the 19th century, some of which relate to the interests of William Temple Franklin.
Armstrong, George; Ashmead, John, ca.1715-1751; Ball, Mary; Burd, Edward Shippen; Clymer, George, 1739-1813; Constable, James; Constable, William; Eddy, Thomas, 1758-1827; Fox, Charles Pemberton, 1792-1866; Fox, George, 1759-1828; Fox, Joseph, ca.1710-1779; Fox, Samuel Mickle, 1763-1808; Hamilton, Gavin; Hill, Henry, 1732-1798; Jones, N. Cantwell; Lukens, John, 1720-1789; Mickle, Samuel; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816; Morris, Robert, 1734-1820; Palmer, Joseph; Pemberton, Israel, 1715-1779; Penn, William,1644-1718.; Pleasants, Samuel; Rhoads, Samuel, Jr.; Strettell, Robert; Tunis, Eliza M. P.; Wallace, William; Waln, Nicholas, 1742-1813; Business Records and Accounts; Land and Speculation; Law; Legal Records; Maps and Surveys; Real property--Pennsylvania; Surveying and Maps
- William Temple Franklin-Charles Pemberton Fox Legal Records, 1731-1793; 2 lin. feet
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1731 Jan. 6; Armstrong, George and Rachel (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1731 Jan. 6; Armstrong, George and Rachel (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1731 Jan. 7; Armstrong, George (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Carval, 1745 May 18; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Carval, 1745 May 18; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Carval, 1746/7 Feb. 6; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Barrack Wright, 1745 May 21; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Peter Rich, 1704 April 17; Baker, John (Box 1)
  - Deed to Joseph Fox, 1741 March 17; Ball, Mary (Box 1)
  - to Charles Hare, 1802 August 16; Bingham, William (Box 1)
  - Deed to Job Goodson, 1724 Oct. 20; Bolton, Prudence, et al. (Box 1)
  - Deed to Joseph Fox, 1766 June 12; Brechel, Andrew and Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Deed to Charles Pemberton Fox and Eliza M. P. Tunis, 1829 July 9; Browne, Peter A (Box 1)
  - Deed to George Fox, 1810 Aug. 16; Burd, Edward Shippen (Box 1)
  - to R. H. Rose, 1832 May 21; Burnside, Judge (Box 1)
  - Deed to Richard Hill, 1724, June 11; Calvert, George and Mary (Box 1)
  - Deed to Ebenezer Large, 1713 June 4; Carpenter, Joshua (Box 1)
  - Deed to Robert Jordan, 1742 April 10; Carpenter, Joshua and Bridget (Box 1)
  - Deed to William Bissell, 1721 April 29; Carpenter, Joshua and Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Luchen, 1751 Nov. 9; Cart, John (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel McCall, 1749 Aug. 24; Carvell, Thomas and Dirck Kyser (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1730 Feb 12; Chapman, Henry (Box 1)
  - Deed to Amalia Morgan, 1723/4 Jan. 3; Church, Edward and Mary (Box 1)
  - Deed to Amalia and Benjamin Morgan, 1723/4 Jan. 4; Church, Edward and Mary (Box 1)
  - Deed to Charles and Hester Pemberton, 1771 Oct. 23; Clymer, George and Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Ashmead, 1723 March 2; Conders, Tunis (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Ashmead, 1723 March 3; Conders, Tunis (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1791 Sept. 18; Constable, William (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1791 Sept. 8; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to [George Fox], 1791 Oct. 4; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1791 Oct. 24; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1792 Jan. 25; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1792 Feb. 9; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1792 June 11; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Also, copy of reply, July 7 1792.
  - to George Fox, 1792 July 12; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - Deed with Miers Buck and Charles Pemberton Fox, 1848 June 7; Davis, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Deed to Joseph Palmer, 1764 Nov. 1; Davis, Thomas and Deborah (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1794 Nov. 17; Drinker, Henry (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1798 June 25; Eddy, Thomas, 1758-1827 (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Rhoads, Jr. of Joseph Palmer's Property, 1770 Dec. 22; Ellicott, Joseph, Sheriff (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1731 Jan. 6; Armstrong, George and Rachel (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1731 Jan. 6; Armstrong, George and Rachel (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1731 Jan 7; Armstrong, George (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Carval, 1745 May 18; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Carval, 1745 May 18; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Carvel, 1746/7 Feb. 6; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Barrack Wright, 1745 May 21; Ashmead, John and Anne (Box 1)
  - Deed to Peter Rich, 1704 April 17; Baker, John (Box 1)
  - Deed to Joseph Fox, 1741 March 17; Ball, Mary (Box 1)
  - to Charles Hare, 1802 August 16; Bingham, William (Box 1)
  - Deed to Job Goodson, 1724 Oct. 20; Bolton, Prudence, et al. (Box 1)
  - Deed to Joseph Fox, 1766 June 12; Brechel, Andrew and Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Deed to Charles Pemberton Fox and Eliza M P Tunis, 1829 July 9; Browne, Peter A (Box 1)
  - Deed to George Fox, 1810 Aug. 16; Burd, Edward Shippen (Box 1)
  - to R. H. Rose, 1832 May 21; Burnside, Judge (Box 1)
    See also Rose, R.H. to Joseph R Ingersoll and William Miller; June 5.1832.
  - Deed to Richard Hill, 1724 June 11; Calvert, George and Mary (Box 1)
  - Deed to Ebenezer Large, 1713 June 4; Carpenter, Joshua (Box 1)
  - Deed to Robert Jordan, 1742 April 10; Carpenter, Joshua and Bridget (Box 1)
  - Deed to William Bissell, 17 April 29; Carpenter, Joshua and Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Luchen, 1751 Nov. 9; Cart, John (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel McCall, 174 Aug. 24; Carvell, Thomas and Dirck Kyser (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1730 Feb. 12; Chapman, Henry (Box 1)
  - Deed to Amalia Morgan, 1723/4 Jan. 3; Church, Edward and Mary (Box 1)
  - Deed to Amalia and Benjamin Morgan, 1723/4 Jan. 4; Church, Edward and Mary (Box 1)
  - Deed to Charles and Hester Pemberton, 1771 Oct. 23; Clymer, George and Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Ashmead, 1723 March 2; Conders, Tunis (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Ashmead, 1723 March 3; Conders, Tunis (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1791 Sept. 18; Constable, William (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1791 Sept. 8; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to [George Fox], 1791 Oct. 4; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1791 Oct. 24; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1792 Jan. 25; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1792 Feb. 9; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1792 June 11; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
    Also copy of reply; July 7, 1792.
  - to George Fox, 1792 July 12; Constable, William and James (Box 1)
  - Deed with Miers Buck and Charles Pemberton Fox, 1848 June 7; Davis, Thomas (Box 1)
  - Deed to Joseph Palmer, 1764 Nov. 1; Davis, Thomas and Deborah (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1794 Nov. 17; Drinker, Henry (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1798 June 25; Eddy, Thomas, 1758-1827 (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Rhoads, Jr. of Joseph Palmer's property, 1770 Dec. 22; Ellicott, Joseph, Sheriff (Box 1)
  - to George Fox, 1794 Feb. 21; Ellis, Daniel (Box 1)
  - Deed to John Davies, 1706 Dec. 25; Evan, Owen ap (Box 1)
  - Deed to Israel Pemberton, 1763 April 16; Evans, Aaron (Box 1)
  - Deed to Thomas Masters, 1699 Feb. 1; Farmer, John (Box 1)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, 1794 July 9; Field, John, et al. (Box 1)
  - Financial Notes. Found originally with Deed of Samuel Mickle to Samuel Jessop, 1760 Aug. 25; Fox, Charles Pemberton, 1792-1866 (Box 2)
  - Deed to John Reakirt, 1855 June 8; Fox, Charles Pemberton, 1792-1866 (Box 2)
  - Deed to William C. Rice, 1833 Sept. 14; Fox, Charles Pemberton, et al. (Box 2)
  - Deed to Eliza M. P. Tunis, 183 July 23; Fox, Charles Pemberton, 1792-1866 (Box 2)
  - Deed to Eliza M. P. Tunis, 1855 Apr. 7; Fox, Charles Pemberton, 1792-1866 (Box 2)
  - Deed to John R Tunis, and to Charles Pemberton Fox, et al., 1819 Feb. 17; Fox, Elizabeth Mary Pemberton (Box 2)
  - Deed, 1795 Oct. 7; Fox, George (Box 2)
  - Deed to Hannah Fox, 1784 Feb. 28; Fox, George (Box 2)
  - Deed to Gavin Hamilton, 1810 Feb. 27; Fox, George (Box 2)
  - Indenture to Thomas Hirst, 1814 Jan. 6; Fox, George (Box 2)
  - Deed to John Littleboy, 1811 July 20; Fox, George (Box 2)
  - Deed to Francis Graham, 1796 Dec. 14; Fox, George and Mary (Box 2)
  - Deed to Francis Graham, 1796 Dec. 14; Fox, George and Mary (Box 2)
  - Deed to Francis Graham, 1796 Dec. 14; Fox, George and Mary (Box 2)
  - Deed to Leonard Rickard, 1795 Jan. 1; Fox, George and Mary (Box 2)
  - Brief of Title to land owned, 1881 Dec.; Fox, George and Sarah (Box 2)
  - Deed to Dennis Flood, 1743 Aug. 24; Fox, Joseph (Box 2)
  - Deed to John Coats, 1755 May 9; Fox, Joseph and Elizabeth, et al. (Box 2)
  - Deed to George Fox, et al.. and to William Holbert and John D Branning, 1867 May 31; Fox, Mary (Box 2)
  - Deed to Joseph House, 1750 May 9; Griffitts, Isaac and Sarah (Box 2)
    Also, Deed of Joseph and Hannah Morris to Esther Pemberton; May 28,1770
  - to George Fox, 1793 July 3; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1793 Oct. 8; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1794 Jan. 1; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1794 May 7; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1794 July 2; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1796 Feb. 25; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1796 Feb. 29; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1796 May 6; Herries, Robert and Co. (Box 2)
    Also memo of George Fox, Aug. 25, 1796.
  - Deed to George Fox, 1795 Aug. 17; Hill, Henry, 1732-1798 (Box 2)
  - Deed to Caleb Ransted, 1716 June 28; Hill, Richard and Hannah (Box 2)
  - Deed to Charles Pemberton Fox, et al., 1829 Feb. 5; Holwell, Edward W. (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1793 May 18; Hulme, John (Box 2)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, 1804 March 30; Hunter, William and Martha (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1792 May 26; Inman, William (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1795 July 25; Jones, Cantwell (Box 2)
  - to George Fox, 1797 June 26; Jones, Cantwell (Box 2)
  - Deed to Andrew Hamilton, 1737 Nov. 16; Jordan, Robert and Mary (Oversize 1)
    Franklin imprint.
  - Bond and Warrant to John Kinsey, et al., 1740 Oct. 15; Jordan, Robert (Box 2)
  - Deed to John Kinsey, et al., 1740 Oct. 15; Jordan, Robert and Mary (Oversize 1)
  - Deed to John Kinsey, et al., 1740 Oct. 15; Jordan, Robert and Mary (Oversize 1)
  - Deed to Jacob Keyser, 1744/5 Feb. 13; Keyser, Dirck and Alice (Box 2)
  - Deed to Nathaniell Ible, 1689 April 24; Ladd, John (Box 3)
    Also, John Smart. Deed to James Portues, June 22, 1693.
  - Deed to George House, 1735 June 14; Large, Ebenezer and Dorothy (Box 3)
  - Deed to Josiah Appleton, 1711 April 25; Large, Ebenezer and Mary (Box 3)
  - Deed to Charles Pemberton Fox of James Clark's property, 1849 Jan. 27; Lelar, Henry (Sheriff) (Box 3)
  - Letter to Nicholas Waln, 1770 Nov. 13 (Box 3)
  - Deed to Joseph Fox, 1763 Nov. 1; Luken, John and Jane (Box 3)
  - Deed of Dower to William Masters, 1773 Jan. 4; Masters, Mary (Box 3)
  - Deed to George Rotch, 1709 Jan. 21; Masters, Thomas (Box 3)
  - Deed to John Care, 1760 Aug. 25; Mickle, Samuel (Box 3)
  - Deed to Samuel Jessop, 1760 Aug. 25; Mickle, Samuel (Box 3)
  - Deed to Thomas Shoemaker, 1760 Aug. 25; Mickle, Samuel (Box 3)
  - Deed to Roger Hawkins, 1712 Nov. 18; Miller, Thomas (Box 3)
    Also Deed of Roger Hawkins to James Dorfus; May 24, 1714.
  - Deed to Benjamin Morgan, 1726 Dec. 30; Morgan, Amalia (Box 3)
  - Deed to John Ashmead, 1726/7 Jan. 2; Morgan, Benjamin and Jane (Box 3)
  - Deed to Benjamin Morgan, 1725 July 1; Morgan, William, Joseph and Samuel (Box 3)
  - Deed to Benjamin Morgan, 1725 July 2; Morgan, William, Joseph and Samuel (Box 3)
  - to George Fox, 1792 April 4; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816 (Box 3)
  - to W.T. Franklin. Bond to invest a certain quantity of stock in the American Funds, 1789-1791; Copies; Morris, Gouverneur, 1752-1816 (Box 3)
  - Bill of Exchange to Sir Robert Herries and Co., 1793 Aug. 21; Morris, Robert (Box 3)
    Also, Protest for non-payment...Dec. 12,1793. Paper
  - to George Fox, [1797 June 30] Friday morning; Morris, Robert, Jr. (Box 3)
    Also Memo of George Fox in re W. T. Franklin, June 30, 1797. Paper
  - Deed to John Parker, 1742 July 2; Murray, Sebastian and Sarah (Box 3)
  - Bond and Warrant to George fox, et al., 1809 Oct. 31; Overton, Thomas (Box 3)
  - Deed to George Rotch, 1711/12 March 5; Owen, Evan and Mary, and John and Ann Carpenter (Box 3)
  - Extract from the Will, 1765 April 24; Palmer, Jonathan (Box 3)
  - Release to Joseph Palmer, 1768 Feb. 20; Palmer, Jonathan and Ann (Box 3)
  - Bond and Mortgage to Samuel Rhoads, Jr., 1766 June 6; Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
    Transferred to Mary Harrison, Oct. 7, 1767, with the acceptance of Israel Pemberton to the above. Paper
  - Bond and Warrant to Samuel Rhoads, Jr., 1766 June 6; Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Bond and Warrant to Samuel Rhoads, Jr., 1768 March 9; Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Map of Land drawn by Thomas Davis, Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Map of land Surveyed by Moses Moon, 1776 Jan.; Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Map of land Surveyed by Paul Preston, 1766 Nov.; Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Map of land Surveyed by Paul Preston, 1766 Nov.; Palmer, Joseph (Box 3)
  - Deed to Samuel Rhoads, Jr., 1766 June 6; Palmer, Joseph and Hannah (Box 3)
  - Deed to Samuel Rhoads, Jr., 1768 Mar. 9; Palmer, Joseph and Hannah (Box 3)
  - Deed to John Kinsey, 1735 Sept. 3; Parker, William H. (Box 3)
  - Deed Tripartite to Samuel and Mary Pleasants, and to Esther Pemberton, 1773 April 2; Pemberton, Joseph and Ann (Box 3)
  - Map of land surveyed by Moses Moon, 1780 April 22; Pemberton, Mary (Box 3)
  - Lease to Robert Jordan, 1738 June 1; Penn, John, Thomas and Richard (Box 3)
  - Grant to Richard Davis, 1692 Aug. 3; Penn, William (Box 3)
  - Grant to Philip Richards, 1692 Dec. 24; Penn, William (Box 3)
  - Deed to George Fox, 1795 Aug. 7; Pennsylvania (Box 3)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, 1795 Aug. 7; Pennsylvania (Box 3)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, 1795 Aug. 7; Pennsylvania (Box 3)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, 1795 Aug. 7; Pennsylvania (Box 3)
  - Deed to John Staple Littler, 1799 Feb. 18; Penrose, Jonathan, Sheriff (Box 3)
  - Deed to William Cooper, 1766 July 7; Perkins, Jacob and Elizabeth (Box 3)
  - Deed to John Hewitt, 1819 March 10; Philips, Zalegman (Box 3)
    Also, John Hewit. Deed to Charles Pemberton Fox, etc., July 3, 1835.
  - Deed to George and Mary Fox, 1719 Apr. 22; Pleasants, Samuel and Mary (Box 3)
  - Deed to Richard Hill, 1719 Dec. 31; Ranstead, Caleb and Mary (Box 4)
  - Deed to Jane Ormes and Jane Ormes, Jr., 1768 Dec. 9; Rhoads, Samuel, Jr. (Box 4)
  - Deed to Israel Pemberton, 1772 Mar. 9; Rhoads, Samuel, Jr. and Sarah (Box 4)
  - Deed to Daniell Cooke, 1693 Aug. 1; Richards, Philip (Box 4)
  - Deed to George Fox, et al., 1823 Mar. 17; Ridgway, Jacob (Box 4)
  - Deed to Israel Pemberton, 1724 Oct. 20; Roch, George (Box 4)
  - Deed to Israel Pemberton, 1724 Oct. 21; Roch, George (Box 4)
  - to Joseph R Ingersoll and William Miller, 1832 June 5; Rose, R. H. (Box 4)
    General note
    See also: Burnside, Judge to R.H. Rose; May 21, 1832.
  - Deed to Samuel and Sarah Barnes, 1752 Mar. 13; Sharp, Hannah (Box 4)
    Also Deed of Hannah Mayleigh to Israel Pemberton, Mar. 13, 1752. Verified by the Lord Mayor of the City of London.
  - Deed to William McMurtie, 1778 Sept.; Shippen, Edward, Jr. and Margaret (Box 4)
    Also, Deed of William McMurtie to Nicholas Waln; 1780 April 17. [Same property involved in both contracts.]
  - Deed against John Cart, 1751 Sept. 20; Stille, Peter (Box 4)
    See also: Stille, Peter. Suit against John Cart; Oct. 7, 1751.
  - Suit against John Cart, 1751 Oct. 7; Stille, Peter (Box 4)
    See also; Stille Peter. Deed against John Cart; 1751 Sept. 20
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle, 1744 April 9; Strettell, Robert and Philotesia (Box 4)
  - Deed Poll to Joseph George, 1819 May 30; Truxton, Thomas, Sheriff (Box 4)
  - Deed Poll to Zalegman Phillips, 1819 Jan. 1; Truxton, Thomas, Sheriff (Box 4)
  - Deed to James Henry, 1846 Mar. 23; Tunis, Eliza M. P. (Box 4)
  - Deed to Charles A Rubicam, 1837 Aug. 1; Tunis, Eliza M. P. (Box 4)
  - Deed to Charles A Rubicam, 1837 Aug. 1; Tunis, Eliza M. P. (Box 4)
  - Deed to Charles A Rubicam, 1845 Jan. 13; Tunis, Eliza M. P. (Box 4)
  - Deed to Jonathan Rubincam, 1855 Feb. 15; Tunis, Eliza M. P. (Box 4)
  - Deed of Confirmation to Jacob F Hoeckley, 1841 April 27; Tunis, Eliza M. P. and Mary D. Fox (Box 4)
  - Deed to to Charles Pemberton Fox, 1849 Jan. 18; Tunis, Eliza M. P. and Mary D. Fox (Box 4)
  - Deed to Charles Pemberton Fox, 1850 Jan. 18; Tunis, Eliza M. P. and Mary D. Fox (Box 4)
  - Deed to Joshua Tittory, 1686 June 19; Turner, Robert (Box 4)
  - Deed to John Widdifield, 1718 Sept. 10; Usher, Jacob and Mary (Box 4)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, et al., 1799 March 26; Wallace, William (Box 4)
  - to Israel Pemberton, 1772 March 8; Waln, Nicholas (Box 4)
  - Deed to George Fox, 1785 Nov. 7; Waln, Nicholas and Sarah (Box 4)
  - Deed to Jacob Perkins, 1771 Nov. 23; Wells, Richard and Rachel (Box 4)
  - Deed to Samuel Mickle Fox, 1784 Nov. 9; West, Thomas and Susanna (Box 4)
  - Deed to Charles and Esther Pemberton, 1771 Jan. 31; Wilson, John (Box 4)
  - Deed to Tunis Conders, 1698/9 Dec. 7; Woostine, John van der (Box 4)
  - Deed to Edward Church, 1721 March 25; Woostine, John van der and Abigail (Box 4)
  - Deed to George House, 1723 May 4; Worrilan, Thomas (Box 4)
  - Deed to Mary Yard, 1725 Dec. 1; Yard, Joseph and Susannah (Box 4)